A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Audiovisual Materials, RG 7 FA1801
Rockefeller Archive Center
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Audiovisual Materials, RG 7
1890-2019
Rockefeller Archive Center
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation
FA1801
11.04 Cubic Feet (30 containers)
107.5 Gigabytes
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
Record Group 7 contains the collection's audiovisual records. They include photographs and slides created for annual reports and newsletters, videos of Knight Foundation events and grant-related projects, and audiotapes of interviews.
Arrangement
As received.
- Artwork, 2001-2016; 1; 0.79 Cubic Feet 1 container
  - 10th Anniversary Gala honoring Adrienne Arsht, 2016 April 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Knight File Number - 5743
    Scope and Contents
    Poster of the Gala includes autographs of the artists. Knight Foundation was honored as a Gala Platinum Sponsor. Color.
  - Knight News Challenge on Libraries Celebration, c. 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5482
    Undated poster of the Knight News Challenge on Libraries Celebration. Color.
- Removable Media, 1950-2013; 2; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Conditions Governing Access
  Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  Throughout this sub-group, printed copies or contact sheets accompany the material on the disks and have been described accordingly. In some cases, a disk was incorrectly filed (e.g. a DVD filed under the CD-ROM series). The incorrect filing was preserved because this scenario exists in cases where multiple disks were used to record the same event/person and were grouped into the same series, despite being on different formats. The reverse is also true for example, disks representing the same person/event may be in two separate series because they were organized by media type. This sub-group is not the only place to find legacy digital material, it represents an earlier organizational effort to group non-paper material into its own record group. Additional legacy digital media can be found throughout each series of the Knight Foundation records.
  - CD-ROM, 1950-2011; 1; 0.1 Cubic Feet
    - Knight Foundation Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes, 1950-1997 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3350
      Copies of Knight Foundation Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes, 1950-March 1997.
    - Lee Hills Hall Dedication - CD-ROM, 1995 April 18 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 817
      Compact Disk containing images of Lee Hills throughout his life and career, and the dedication of Lee Hills Hall at the University of Missouri's School of Journalism on 4/18/95. The compact disk must be used with the accompanying 3 1/2" floppy disk. Two sets of the CD and floppy disks are contained in this box.
    - Lee Hills Hall Dedication - Floppy Disk, 1995 April 18 (Box 1)
      File Plan
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Printed Index to CD-ROMS, 2000 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation, ten CD-ROMs of historical images, including Charles and Clara Knight (parents of JS and JLK); JSK as a child, young man, and with his children, wives, and grandchildren; JLK as young man, with his wife and children (including images at his daughters' weddings and during family vacations). Also images of JSK and JLK at work (meeting of the BOD of Knight-Ridder, at the Akron Beacon Journal, at the Miami Herald ground breaking ceremony, etc.) and at work-related events (including images of JSK with John F. Kennedy, Richard Nixon, and JSK and JLK with Lee Hills, Ben Maidenburg, Alvah Chapman, C.C. Gibson, etc. (four folders with index). The images were copied from the personal collections of children of James L. Knight, the Archives of the University of Akron and the Knight Fdn Archives and other sources. (Photographs of some of the scanned images were placed in the Archives photo collection).
      Knight File Number - 1863
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 1, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 2, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 3, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 4, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 5, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 6, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 7, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 8, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 9, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation - Disk 10, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation, Medium Resolution - Disk 1, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 2260
      Medium resolution scans of a total of 313 images. These duplicate other images on CD-roms.
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation, Medium Resolution - Disk 2, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary, John S. and James L. Knight Foundation, Medium Resolution - Disk 3, 2000 January 26 (Box 1)
    - Knight Foundation Website Snapshots - Test, 2002 July 16 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 2536
      Providing a "snapshot" of the contents of the Knight Foundation website on July 16, 2002.
    - Knight Foundation Website Snapshots - Live, 2002 July 16 (Box 1)
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, Charlotte, NC - Contact Sheets, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat for orchestra directors in Charlotte, North Carolina. One CD, containing 5 images scanned at very high resolution, with color contract proof sheets of 150 photos. NOTE: Contact the photographer at LOF Productions for authorization and JPEGs.
      Knight File Number - 3018
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, Charlotte, NC, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, Brooklyn, 2003 May 10 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3015
      Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat at Brooklyn, New York. Photos are of participants and include Penny McPhee, Lisa Versaci, and MofM consultant Tom Wolf. Includes a demonstration of the Concert Companion on PDA (a hand-held computer with screen) by Roland Valiere. Contains one cd, with 12 jpeg and tiff images and contact sheets.
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Retreat, Brooklyn - Contact Sheets, 2003 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Concert Companion Test, 2003 August 20 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3016
      Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Concert Companion test. Concertgoers in Saratoga, NY got to follow along with program notes in real time during a pilot test of the handheld Concert Companion. A grant to the Kansas City Symphony helped symphony executive Roland Valliere develop the new device. Contains complete color contact sheets plus CD disk of all photos in JPEG.
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Initiative Concert Companion Test - Contact Sheet, 2003 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Knight Commission Meeting - College Sports - Disk 1, 2004 February 2 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4440
      CD and contact sheets (taken by Lisa Helfert) at a Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics Meeting in Washington, DC. Commissioners met with NCAA president, coaches and television executives as it continued its work seeking reform of college sports.
    - Knight Commission Meeting - College Sports - Disk 2, 2004 February 2 (Box 1)
    - Knight Commission Meeting - College Sports - Contact Sheets, 2004 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Knight Foundation 2003 Annual Report - AR1, 2004 April 20 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 2707
      Files of the final version of the Knight Foundation 2003 annual report.
    - Knight Foundation 2003 Annual Report - AR2, 2004 April 20 (Box 1)
    - Knight Foundation 2003 Annual Report - AR3, 2004 April 20 (Box 1)
    - Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics Meeting, 2004 May 24 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4441
      CD and contact sheets (taken by Lisa Helfert) at a Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics Meeting in Washington, DC.
    - Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics Meeting - Contact Sheets, 2004 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Working@Knight Newsletter Archive, 2002-2007 (Box 1)
      Working@Knight every issue 2001-2007.
      Knight File Number - 2732
    - Knight Foundation Website Webmaster's Backup - Disk 1, 2004 May 17 (Box 1)
      Two CDs containing entire contents of www.knightfdn.org website.
    - Knight Foundation Website Webmaster's Backup - Disk 2, 2004 May 17 (Box 1)
    - New Employee Portraits, 2004 December 6 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 2868
      CD rom with color portraits of: Anne Corriston, Community Liaison Program Officer; Beverly Blake, Community Liaison Program Officer, and Sharon Moshavi, Communications Manager, all of whom started at Knight Foundation in December 2004. Also includes thumbnail prints.
    - New Employee Portraits - Thumbnail Prints, 2004 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Thumbnail prints of: Anne Corriston, Community Liaison Program Officer; Beverly Blake, Community Liaison Program Officer, and Sharon Moshavi, Communications Manager, all of whom started at Knight Foundation in December 2004.
    - Magic of Music Orchestra Closing Retreat - Disk 1, 2005 January 8-9
      Knight File Number - 3293
      Magic of Music Orchestra Closing Retreat in Miami, FL. DVD set of the discussion with Michael Tilson Thomas and Christoph Eschenbach, moderated by Tom Wolf.
      - Magic of Music Orchestra Closing Retreat - Disk 2
      - Magic of Music Orchestra Closing Retreat - Lincoln Theater Music Directors, Miami Beach, 2005 January 10
        Magic of Music Orchestra Closing Retreat in Miami, FL. Photos are of participants and include Michael Tilson Thomas appearing via satellite from San Francisco. Contains one cd, and contact sheets. Harvey Bilt photographer.
    - Knight Commission Meeting, 2005 February 7 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4442
      Photos (taken by Harvey Bilt) at a Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics Meeting in Miami, FL. Includes a group shot of the Commission members.
    - Knight Commission Meeting, 2005 February 7 (Box 1)
    - Knight Commission Meeting - Thumbnail Prints, 2005 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Joe Ervin and Lisa Versaci Goodbye Party, 2005 May 2 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3309
      Photos of staff going to a party for departing colleagues, Joe Ervin and Lisa Versaci.
    - Joe Ervin and Lisa Versaci Goodbye Party - Thumbnail Prints, 2005 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Knight Foundation Staff Photos - Disk 1 (Current Staff: A through Mojica), 2005 March 2 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3349
      Photos of Knight Foundation staff, both current and former, and trustees.
    - Knight Foundation Staff Photos - Disk 2 (Current Staff: Naida through Z, Trustees, Former Staff), 2005 March 2 (Box 1)
    - Knight Commission Meeting, 2005 May 23 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4443
      Photos (taken by Lisa Helfert) at a Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics Meeting in Washington, DC.
    - Knight Commission Meeting - Contact Sheets, 2005 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Hodding Carter Staff Retirement Party - Photos by Philip Francis, 2005 June 30 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3310
      Staff retirement party for departing president, Hodding Carter held at Books & Books.
    - Hodding Carter Staff Retirement Party - Video by Robbie Adams, 2005 June 30 (Box 1)
    - Hodding Carter Staff Retirement Party - Thumbnail Prints, 2006 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "The Future of Community Foundations" Webcast, 2005 July 7 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4411
      Knight Foundation webcast featuring Mark Kramer of Foundation Strategy Group (FSG).
    - Knight Commission Meeting, 2006 January 30 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4444
    - Knight Commission Meeting - Contact Sheets, 2006 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Knight Foundation Asset and Stock History Project, 2006 March (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3707
      Financial information assembled upon the sale of Knight Ridder. Includes many charts and graphs. Two copies.
    - Knight Foundation Newsletter and Publications, 2005 May-2006 June (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3804
      One CD-Rom containing: Working@Knight newsletter - editions of May 2005 through June 2006 (13 PDF format files); News@Knight newsletter - editions of winter 2005 through February 2006 (4 PDF format files); News@Knight newsletter - individual articles in HTML format for editions #61-#67; News in a New America publication (PDF format); Magic of Music series publications #1-#5 (PDF format); Keeping Secrets special publication (PDF format); "Final" Magic of Music special publication DRAFT edition (PDF format).
    - Knight Foundation Art Collection, 2003 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4760
      Photos of Knight Foundation art work.
    - Knight Foundation Art Collection, 2006 (Box 1)
    - Immigration Debate, 2008 May 15 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4741
      The debate, part of the National Discussion Debate Series, and hosted by Miller Center of Public Affairs, was underwritten by KF. It presented two pro and two con speakers on the resolution: "Our national interests require a path to citizenship for the 12 million illegal immigrants presently here."
    - Alberto Ibarguen's Visit to China, 2008 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4445
      Photos of Alberto Ibarguen's visit to China with Sam Grogg, Dean of the School of Communications, University of Miami. Ibarguen was visiting Tsinghua University in China. KF made a grant to the International Center for Journalists (20070003) to start a global business journalism program at the University.
    - Alberto Ibarguen's Visit to China - Thumbnail Prints, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Alberto Ibarguen's Remarks at Council on Foundations Conference - MP3, 2007 September 20 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5881
      Video and MP3 recording of Alberto Ibarguen's remarks at the Council on Foundations Conference on Community Foundations and Family Foundations, San Francisco, CA. In his remarks, Alberto first announced the proposed gathering which became the Media Learning Seminars. The reference to the MLS is at 19:41.
    - Alberto Ibarguen's Remarks at Council on Foundations Conference - Video, 2007 September 20 (Box 1)
    - Summit Artspace Reception Announcing Akron Arts Grants, 2010 June 24 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5078
      Photographs taken at reception announcing grants of $700,000 to Akron arts groups, including a major grant to renovate the Summit Artspace, which is housed in the old Akron Beacon Journal offices. Announcement was part of a launch of Knight's new national arts program and featured remarks by Dennis Scholl. Several trustees and staff members were in attendance.
    - John S. Knight Speech to the Akron Chamber of Commerce, 1959-2011 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4912
      Digital copy of an audiotape of a 1958 speech by John Knight at the Golden Anniversary meeting of the Chamber. Included is a transcript of the entire meeting (79 minutes, 54 seconds). Mr. Knight spoke of Akron's past, his father, and current events, both local and national.
    - John S. Knight Speech to the Akron Chamber of Commerce - Printed Version, 1958-2011 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - John S. Knight Speeches - Preceedings at John S. Knight Testimonial Dinner, Sheraton Hotel, 1964 November 16 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4942
      Digital copies of several audiotapes: 1) Proceedings at John S. Knight Testimonial Dinner, November 16, 1964 at the Sheraton Hotel in Akron, OH. Includes remarks by James L. Knight, an introduction by E.J. Thomas and remarks by John S. Knight, looking back on his fifty year career in the newspaper business. (79:55 minutes) Includes a transcript of the audiotape. 2) John S. Knight's Question and Answer Session at the Poor Richard Club, January 17, 1972, in Philadelphia, PA. Knight answers written questions on current events and the future of the United States. (28:06 minutes). Both files were copied from the JSK collection, University of Akron.
    - John S. Knight Speeches - John S. Knight's Question and Answer Session, Poor Richard Club, 1972 January 17 (Box 1)
    - John S. Knight Speeches - Printed Version, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Printed transcript of 1964 JSK Testimonial Dinner.
    - John Shively Knight Memorial booklet, 1981 June-2011 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4943
      Scanned images of the booklet, published by the Akron Beacon Journal, and honoring the life of John S. Knight.
    - John Shively Knight Memorial booklet - PDF, 1981 June-2011 (Box 1)
  - Hard Drive, 2009; 2; 0.1 Cubic Feet
    - Ceremony and Reception Honoring W. Gerald Austen, Akron, OH, 2009 September 9 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4765
      A Mac-compatible removeable drive containing 90 gigabytes (2 hours) of raw video taken at the ceremony honoring Dr. Austen on his retirement from the KF board.
  - DVD, 1957-2013; 3; 0.1 Cubic Feet
    - Reinventing Akron: Stories of a Generation, 2001 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4597
      DVD produced for the Akron Community Foundation featuring oral history interviews with recipients of the Bert Polsky Award (Akron civic award), and photographs. The contributions of John S. Knight, Ben Maidenburg and E.J. Thomas are discussed. One of the interviewees is former trustee, John Ong.
    - Penny@Knight: Penny McPhee Commemorative DVD, 2004 March 26 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 2706
      DVD consisting of pictures of Penny McPhee, Knight Foundation's arts and culture program officer and, later, chief program officer, 1990-2004. The photographs commemorate her time at Knight Foundation and include scenes from work and play. The DVD contains music.
    - Penny@Knight: Penny McPhee Commemorative DVD - CD-R version without music, 2004 March 26 (Box 1)
      CD version, without music, consisting of pictures of Penny McPhee, Knight Foundation's arts and culture program officer and, later, chief program officer, 1990-2004. The photographs commemorate her time at Knight Foundation and include scenes from work and play.
    - Lloyd Schermer, Sculptor - Interview, 2004 November 15 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 2867
      Documenting the installation of a mixed-media sculpture by Lloyd Schermer in the Board Conference room. The sculpture consists, primarily, of old type. Schermer, a retired newspaper executive, was also interviewed by Robbie Adams re: his acquaintance with the Knight brothers and Alvah Chapman. (20 minutes).
    - Lloyd Schermer, Sculptor - Video files and photos, R. Adams, 2004 November (Box 1)
      Data DVD contains a stream file useful for future editing.
    - Lloyd Schermer, Sculptor - Biographical Information, 2004 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Biographical sketch of Schermer, written by Schermer.
    - Video History of Charles Clark, 2004 December 22 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3311
      One DVD of an interview with Charles Clark, former Knight Foundation trustee. Clark was interviewed by Hodding Carter (off camera). The interview concentrated on Clark's experiences at Knight Foundation and the Knight brothers.
    - Video History of Alvah Chapman - Part 1, 2004 December 22 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3312
      A 2-DVD interview with Alvah Chapman, former Knight Foundation trustee. Chapman was interviewed by Hodding Carter (off camera). The interview concentrated on Chapman's experiences at Knight Foundation, Miami Herald, and the Knight brothers.
    - Video History of Alvah Chapman - Part 2, 2004 December 22 (Box 1)
    - Hodding Carter III Interview by Andrew Cohen, ICFJ, 2004 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4598
      Interview with Hodding Carter at the KF offices by Andrew Cohen, International Committee of Foreign Journalists.
    - Bill Friday - Vignette/Remarks, 2005 January 25 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4446
      Bill Friday, who was awarded the NCAA's Gerald R. Ford leadership award in 2005. Friday's work for the Knight Commission was mentioned. Includes biographical information.
    - Knight Commission Report: Newshour with Jim Lehrer - PBS Coverage, 2005 March 17 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4447
      Segment of the News Hour with Jim Lehrer in which reporter Gwen Ifil reported on the findings of the Knight Commission with respect to graduation rates of student athletes.
    - First Amendment Video (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 3351
    - Future of the First Amendment, News Conference, Freedom Forum, Arlington, VA, 2005 January 31 (Box 1)
    - First Amendment Survey - Cable Market, HLN-CNN Headline News 1:30PM, 2005 January 31 (Box 1)
    - First Amendment Survey - New York Market, WNYW Fox News at 6, 6:11PM, 2005 January 31 (Box 1)
    - First Amendment Survey - AVI files, 2005 (Box 1)
      1. Cable Market, CNN, Lou Dobbs Tonight, 2/14/2005, 3:24PM (03:06). 2. Roanoke-Lynchburg Market, WSET, The Night Team, 2/1/2005, 11:09PM (01:22) 3. Cable Market, MSNBC, The Abrams Report, 2/1/2005, 10:51PM (02:01) 4. Cable Market, FNC (Fox News Channel), Studio B with Shepard Smith, 1/31/2005, 12:46PM (00:37)
    - First Amendment Survey - AVI - News Magazine Market, The Daily Buzz 6:20AM, 2005 February 2 (Box 1)
    - Channel One News First Amendment Survey, 2005 March 10 (Box 1)
    - Hodding Carter III Tribute Video, 2005 September 19 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4599
      DVD slide show of Hodding Carter 1) commemorating his career before and with the Knight Foundation and 2) "crazy legs" commemorating his love of dancing. 2 copies
    - Tune In To Teens: How Newsrooms Connect with High Schools and Why Your Newsroom Should, Too, 2005 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4761
      The Radio and Television News Directors Foundation created the DVD to share success stories and inspire other progessional electronic journalists to join in. The Foundation and DVD were supported by a grant from KF.
    - The Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics: A Summit on the Collegiate Athlete Experience - Disk 1, 2006 January 30 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4448
      DVD Movie of the summit, which was chaired by Alberto Ibarguen.